<!--
    legal.xml

    Copyright (c) 2006-2007, Jack D. Unrue
-->
<chapter id="legal">
  <title>Legal Notices</title>
  <para>
    Copyright &#x00A9; 2006-2007, Jack D. Unrue &lt;jdunrue at gmail dot com&gt;
  </para>
  <para role="normal">
    Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without 
    modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met: 
  </para>
  <para role="normal">
    1. Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, 
    this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.
  </para>
  <para role="normal">
    2. Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright 
    notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the 
    documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution.
  </para>
  <para role="normal">
    3. Neither the names of the authors nor the names of its contributors may 
    be used to endorse or promote products derived from this software without 
    specific prior written permission.
  </para>
  <para>
    THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE AUTHORS AND CONTRIBUTORS "AS IS" AND ANY
    EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED
    WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE
    DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS AND CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE 
    FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL 
    DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR 
    SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER 
    CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, 
    OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE 
    OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
  </para>

  <bridgehead renderas="sect2">Trademarks</bridgehead>
  <para role="normal">
    Windows&#x00ae; is a registered trademark of Microsoft Corporation. Allegro CL&#x00ae;
    is a registered trademark of Franz Inc. LispWorks&#x00ae; is a registered trademark of
    LispWorks Ltd. All other trademarks used are owned by their respective owners.
  </para>
</chapter>
